<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Reasons for taking off the duty upon the glass and earthen manufactures</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28713</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99832208</idno>
  <idno type="VID">198928</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240915004</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R512</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99832208</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99832208e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28713)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 198928)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 21242:125)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Reasons for taking off the duty upon the glass and earthen manufactures</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Pottery, English --  Great Britain --  Taxation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Glass trade --  Great Britain --  Taxation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:198928:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:198928:1"/>
            <head>REASONS For taking off the DUTY upon the Glass and Earthen Manufactures.</head>
            <p>IF Manufacturing any Commodities in this Kingdom, which were former<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly brought from Foreign Parts, ought to be Encouraged.</p>
            <p>If such Manufactures that are produced chiefly by the Labour of the Poor (who are always Exempted in our Taxations) ought to be che<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rished.</p>
            <p>If our Woollen Manufacture, tho' supported with our English Wool (which no Nation can equal) has notwithstanding all the Assistance and Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment that can be given: and if Manufactures that are as easily made in Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Parts as in this Nation, ought by parity of Reason to be more Encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raged.</p>
            <p>If the Lustring Manufacture be deservedly kept among us by all possible ways and means to Support and Encourage it, rather than forced home again to <hi>France,</hi> by Burthening it with Duties.</p>
            <p>And if it be the Wisdom and Practice of all Nations to Assist and En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courage the Manufactures of useful Commodities among them.</p>
            <p>Then there is all the reason in the World to set the Glass and Earthen Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufactures free from the present Duty that is upon it, which has already almost and will (if not quickly taken off) quite destroy it.</p>
            <p>And then the <hi>Hollanders, Venetians, &amp;c.</hi> may have cause to Rejoice at the return of their Trade, but we shall certainly have reason to repent the Loss of so useful a Manufacture.</p>
            <p>If several work Houses were forced to give over soon after the Duty was laid, not being able to bear the Burthen of it: If others have been since Ruined by it, if those that remain are not without great Difficulties Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported, and that they do not Manufacture near the Quantities as formerly; if many of our Manufacturers, are gone out of the Nation, if setting up work Houses in <hi>Scotland</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> since this Duty; and if many of the Poor that were Employ'd in these Manufactures are forced to the Parish for Maintenance, which are all matters of Fact, be Arguments sufficient to Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince us, that if this Duty be not quickly taken off, these Manufactures will be Extinguished; it then behooves us, no longer to hearken to the plau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sible, but fallacious Pretences of those that gain by the Collection of the Duty, who therefore argue for the Continuance of it; but that we immediate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly apply the most proper means for Reviving and Supporting it.</p>
            <p>T'is very strange, That all our other Manufactures (properly so call'd) should be under a <hi>Noli me tangere;</hi> and this of Glass and Earthen Ware (which as much merits our Regard as any other) should be singled out to be crushed to Ruine.</p>
            <p>The Duty arising from it is so inconsiderable, that it can be no Argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment for its Continuance; and should it produce as great a Sum as the mista<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken Proposers pretended, yet the Premises considered, 'twould be the Interest of the Nation, to take it off, and raise an Equivolent any other way; which may be done, by laying a Duty upon Commodities of more necessary and gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Use among us, and that will not be attended with such ill Consequences, as this upon Glass and Earthen Wares.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:198928:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:198928:2"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>